RYAN TANI, Conductor

RyanYTani@gmail.com • RyanYTani.com

103 Paisley Ct. Apt. G • Bozeman, MT, 59715 • (801) 703-5629

Finalist, Asst. Cond./MD Youth Orch **Illinois Symphony** 2022 Oregon Symphony Finalist, Asst. Conductor Audition 2022 **Utah Symphony** Finalist, Asst. Conductor Audition 2021 Bozeman Symphony **Cover Conductor** 2021 - Present Occasional Symphony **Music Director** 2018 - 2021

Served as chair of the Programming Committee, developed innovative programs that explore many venues in the Baltimore area, and supported Baltimore composers through commissions (average 7/yr).

Conducting Fellow Yale Philharmonia

Assisted Maestro Oundian and all guest conductors for Philharmonia concerts, preparing the orchestra frequently for guests as well as conducting subscription concerts. During COVID, I also developed curricula for remote-learning students and have served as producer for recorded concerts.

New Music New Haven

Resident Conductor

2019 - 2021

Directed performances of new compositions by composition students and faculty alike, working with composition chair Aaron Jay Kernis, leading all new music components for the Yale Philharmonia and NMNH.

Montgomery Philharmonic

Conducting Fellow

2017 - 2019

Assisted Music Director with up to six concerts per year in Montgomery County, MD. Recruited and served as chorusmaster for several choral-orchestral performances over my term, including the Brahms Requiem and Beethoven 9.

Chesapeake Youth Symphony Orchestra

Assistant Conductor

2016 - 2019

Served as principal conductor of the Preparatory Orchestra (grades 3-6 strings) – I programmed pedagogically appropriate repertoire that helped create a strong upward lineage to advanced ensembles. Served as assistant conductor for and regularly rehearsed both the Concert and Symphony Orchestras (grades 7-12), running sectionals, and conducting when the Music Director was not present.

COSMIC Symphony

Assistant Conductor

2016 - 2018

Served as Assistant Conductor to Vladimir Lande, frequently covering rehearsals in California, MD and conducting in community concerts.

USC Concerto Chamber Orchestra

Founder, Music Director

2012 - 2015

Founded and conducted a student-led and directed orchestra in Southern California which provided high level performance opportunities to non-music-majors. I served as chair of the Programming Committee, operations manager, and librarian, among other duties.

Other Conducting Opportunities

Mississippi Valley Orchestra	Guest Conductor	2022
Yale Philharmonia	Guest Conductor	2022
Choir of the Cathedral of the Madeleine	Guest Conductor	2016, 2021, 2022

Guest conducted Bruckner's Te Deum for the annual St. Cecilia Day concert in 2021, and Britten's "Hymn to St. Cecilia" for the same concert in 2016.

Waterbury Symphony

Guest Conductor

Summer 2020

Conducted an outdoor performance of the Vivaldi Four Seasons from keyboard.

Baltimore Concert Opera

Guest Conductor

2019

Conducted a partially staged performance of Wagner's Flying Dutchman for three performances.

Peabody Community Chorus

Cover Conductor

2018

Prepared an amateur volunteer chorus of 50 singers for a performance of Bernstein's MASS.

Chamber Music Institute

Principal Conductor

2017

Conducted orchestra, coached chamber music courses, and taught violin for young musicians aged 8-18. Opera Études Conductor

Conducted new operas written by Peabody Conservatory student composers.

2016

Relevant Experience

Billings Symphony Orchestra

2004 - 2011

• Serve as Audio/Video Editing Assistant, working to streamline concert editing for later digital release on both radio and video platforms.

University of Southern California

2011 - 2015

• Minor in Computer Science – work in databases demonstrating a technical proficiency with file storage, data analysis, and other related technical tools that might be necessary for working with an arts organization.

Festivals and Workshops

Cabrillo Festival Conductor's Workshop	2021
Will serve as one of 8 Associates.	
Charleston Symphony Conducting Workshop	2019
Masterclass with Mark Gibson culminating in final concert with Charleston Symphony	
International Conducting Workshop and Festival	2019
Masterclass with Larry Rachleff and Donald Schleicher	
Ithaca International Conducting Masterclass	2018
Masterclass with Larry Rachleff culminating in concert with Cornell Chamber Orchestra	
Conducting Masterclass & Workshop Series	2018
Masterclass with Donald Schleicher	
Baltimore Symphony Orchestra	2016, 2017
Masterclass with Marin Alsop	
Eastern Music Festival	2016

Awards

Yale School of Music	Dean's Award	2021	
Given by Dean Robert Blocker to one student each graduating class, demonstrating highest artistic and			
academic excellence.			
ACDA Choral Conducting Competition	First Prize, Undergraduate Division	2015	

Selected as one of 8 Fellows for summer festival in Greensboro, NC under Gerard Schwarz.

Education

Yale University, School of Music, MMA Conducting, May 2021		
Advisor: Peter Oundjian		
Peabody Institute of Johns Hopkins University, MM Conducting '17	2015 - 2017	
Advisors: Marin Alsop, Markand Thakar		
University of Southern California, BM Vocal Performance, '15	2011 - 2015	
Conducting Advisors: Donald Brinegar, Larry Livingston, Jo-Michael Scheibe		
Other Conducting Teachers: Grant Cooper, José-Luis Novo, Larry Rachleff, Donald Schleicher,		
Gerard Schwarz		